A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Rockefeller University Press, Research Profiles FA947
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Rockefeller University Press, Research Profiles
1980-1990
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University Press
FA947
1 Cubic Feet 1 box.
1 box.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
Biographical / Historical
In May of 1980 The Rockefeller University began a new quarterly publication. Each issue is to profile an area of research at The Rockefeller, not only to report on what's new and promising but also to convey something of the process of science.
It is written and edited by Fulvio Bardossi and Judith N. Schwartz of the University's Public Information Office.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for scholarly research.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 539
Medical technology; Science -- Study and teaching; Medical sciences; Medical education; Life sciences; Medicine, Preventive; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Biology -- Research; Medical research; Rockefeller University Press
- Research profiles, 1980-1990
  - no. 1: Gene control and enzymatic zippers (Vincent Allfrey), Summer 1980 (Box 1)
  - no. 2: Cultivating killers. (William Trager), Fall 1980 (Box 1)
  - no. 3: Birdman. (Peter Marler), Winter 1980 (Box 1)
  - no. 4: Structures. (Emil C. Gotschlich), Spring 1981 (Box 1)
  - no. 5: Biology by the numbers. (Joel E. Cohen), Summer 1981 (Box 1)
  - no. 6: Scientist in the making (Alice Bendix Gottlieb), Fall 1981 (Box 1)
  - no. 7: Particles of light, webs of interaction. (Floyd Ratliff), Winter 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - no. 8: Elegant molecules. (Stanford Moore), Spring 1982 (Box 1)
  - no. 9: Of cabbages and kings: the heme pathway. (Attallah Kappas), Summer 1982 (Box 1)
  - no. 10: Oncogenes evolutionary hitchhikers. (Hidesaburo Hanafusa), Fall 1982 (Box 1)
  - no. 11: God's pickpockets. (Abraham Pais), Winter 1982-1983 (Box 1)
  - no. 12: Stalking the macrophage. (Zanvil Cohn), Spring 1983 (Box 1)
  - no. 13: Busy in the meadow. (Vincent Dole), Summer 1983 (Box 1)
  - no. 14: Mentors and colleagues. (Clarence Connelly), Fall 1983 (Box 1)
  - no. 15: The Trick of the Tryp (George Cross), Winter 1983-1984 (Box 1)
  - no. 16: Messengers to the Brain (Bruce S. McEwen), Spring 1984 (Box 1)
  - no. 17: An Unconventional Traveler. (Christian de Duve), Summer 1984 (Box 1)
  - no. 18: Cholesterol-Watching (Edward H. Ahrens, Jr), Fall 1984 (Box 1)
  - no. 19: Cholesterol-Watching II: Genes. (Jan L. Breslow), Winter 1984-1985 (Box 1)
  - no. 20: The Road to Stockholm. (R. Bruce Merrifield), Spring 1985 (Box 1)
  - no. 21: More Than Skin Deep. (D. Martin Carter), Summer 1985 (Box 1)
  - no. 22: The Fat's in the Fire. (Jules Hirsch), Fall 1985 (Box 1)
  - no. 23: Sensible Animals. (Donald Griffin), Winter 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - no. 24: A Matter of Concern. (Dennis Stark), Spring 1986 (Box 1)
  - no. 25: Movers and Shapers. (David Luck), Summer 1986 (Box 1)
  - no. 26: The Surface of a Small Cell. (Alexander Tomasz), Fall 1986 (Box 1)
  - no. 27: Eos' Oversight. (Anthony Cerami), Spring 1987 (Box 1)
  - no. 28: Dr. Flexner's Experiment (Dr. Simon Flexner), Summer 1987 (Box 1)
  - no. 29: Sense and Synapse (Paul Greengard), Fall 1987 (Box 1)
  - no. 30: A Fine Playground (Norton D. Zinder), Winter 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - no. 31: Oswald Avery and the Sugar-Coated Microbe (Oswald Avery), Spring 1988 (Box 1)
  - no. 32: Fast Track Physics (Konstantin Goulianos/Rodney L. Cool), Fall 1988 (Box 1)
  - no. 33: Brainwork (Donald W. Pfaff), Spring 1989 (Box 1)
  - no. 34: Friend of the Good Earth (René J. Dubos), Summer 1989 (Box 1)
  - Genespeak (Michael W. Young), Winter 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Report on the President (Joshua Lederberg), Spring 1990 (Box 1)
  - "Mrs. L" (Rebecca C. Lancefield), Summer 1990 (Box 1)